guru.com 2019-12-27

# Privacy Policy - Guru

## Overview

Guru.com is firmly committed to the privacy of its members. Guru.com works hard to earn and keep your trust, so it adheres to the following principles to protect your privacy: 

  * Guru.com does not rent or sell your personally identifiable information to third parties.

  * Guru.com does not share your contact information with other users or third parties without your consent.

  * Any personally identifiable information that you provide to Guru.com will be secured with industry standard protocols and technology.

## Information Collection

Guru.com is an online marketplace that connects businesses with Freelancers. When you visit Guru.com you provide two types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected by Guru.com and website use information collected by Guru.com as you interact with the Guru.com website (the "Website"). 

When you register with Guru.com as a Freelancer or as an Employer, you provide certain personal information, including, your name, your email address and your address. Additionally, when you establish your profile as a Freelancer or as an Employer you will provide information relating to your skills, experience, education level, compensation, work availability, geographic region and self-evaluation. Such information does not identify the specificity of the individual member. Freelancers are not required to, but have the option to display their contact information (i.e. name, address, phone number, email address, etc.) to Employers who conduct searches of the Guru.com database. 

When you enter the Website, Guru.com collects your IP address. This information is gathered for all Guru.com visitors. In addition, Guru.com stores certain information from your browser using "cookies." A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. Guru.com uses session ID cookies to confirm that users are logged in. These cookies terminate once the user closes the browser. By default, Guru.com uses a persistent cookie that stores your login ID (but not your password) to make it easier for you to login when you return to the Website. Guru.com members must have cookies enabled on their browser. Note: Cookie preferences are set within each browser's Internet options/preferences. 

If you post a information on a bulletin board, or participate in a public message board, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you choose to provide there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. Guru.com is not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. 

Guru.com is the sole owner of the information collected through the Website. 

### Information Use

Guru.com will not sell or rent any collected information to third parties. Guru.com will not share your contact information with other users or third parties except in connection with possible employment and with your express consent. All registered Guru.com members click the "I AGREE" checkbox on the registration form to agree to the Guru.com Privacy Policy and Terms of Service. Accordingly, all registered users agree that certain profile information is accessible to other registered users. 

Guru.com records IP addresses for system administration purposes. This information is used to diagnose server problems, monitor traffic patterns, analyze trends, administer the Website, track member user patterns, and identify the most popular areas of the Website to deliver content most relevant to registered members. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information and are only used to gather broad demographic information for aggregate use, except in the case of fraud. 

Guru.com reserves the right to share aggregated demographic information with its partners and/or advertisers, such information will not be linked to personal information that identifies registered users, except in the case of fraud. 

### Google Analytics & AdWords

Google Analytics: We use Google Analytics tracking to review visitor website activities, including: page views, source and time spent on our website. The collected information is depersonalized and is displayed as numbers, meaning it cannot be tracked back to individuals. This will help to protect your privacy. Using Google Analytics, we learn how to give you a better visitor experience. 

Google AdWords: Using Google AdWords tracking codes, we can see which pages help lead to different conversions on Guru.com. This allows us to better use our paid advertising budget. 

Remarketing With Google Analytics: We use the Google Analytics remarketing code to log when visitors view specific web pages. This allows us to provide targeted advertising in the future. 

  * Third-party vendors, including Google, may show Guru.com's ads across the internet.

  * Guru.com and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on a user's past visits to Guru.com.

### Opting Out:

Visitors can opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using their [Ads Settings.](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated) Additionally, visitors can opt out of the [Google Analytics Browser Add-On](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

### Links

The Website contains links to other websites and is not responsible for the privacy practices of such websites. Guru.com encourages its members to read the privacy policies of all websites. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by Guru.com. 

### Security

Guru.com takes industry standard protocols and technology to protect registered user information. Guru.com is a VeriSign Secure Site. Please click the VeriSign logo at the bottom of any page in the website to view our official VeriSign certificate. All transactions performed through Guru.com are conducted in a Secure Socket Layer (SSL) session. The Secure Socket Layer encrypts all transaction data for transmittal in a format that prevents data theft. This process protects all private information from being disclosed to third parties. While on a secure page, the lock icon at the bottom of a Web browser (i.e. Firefox or Chrome) becomes locked. 

Guru.com also protects registered user information offline. All registered user information is restricted within our offices. Servers used to store personally identifiable information are housed in a secure, supervised environment. In addition, only Guru.com employees who need specific information to perform a task are granted access to personally identifiable information. 

### Mandatory Communications

Guru.com sends all newly registered users a welcome email to verify their email addresses. At times, Guru.com sends service announcements to its registered Employers and Freelancers. Registered Users cannot unsubscribe from service announcements that discuss upcoming changes that affect their Guru.com accounts. In addition, we communicate with registered members via personal emails or phone calls to provide requested services. 

### Optional Communications

Registered users receive monthly e-newsletters containing information on Guru.com products, services and announcements. Occasionally, registered users receive e-postcards that highlight special Guru.com announcements and features. Registered users can opt-out of the above listed communications. Please see our Choice/Opt-out section below. 

### Choice/Opt-out

Upon registration, users can opt-out of Guru.com's option communications. Additionally, registered users can, at any time, modify their Guru.com email (service announcement) preferences by updating their account information. 

### Notification of Changes

Guru.com reserves the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If Guru.com alters its Privacy Policy, it will promptly post all changes in the Employer and Freelancer Announcement areas. By continuing to use Guru.com after changes have been made to this policy, you are consenting to the changes. 

## Disclaimers

### Social Login Disclaimer

Social Logins allow for single sign-up using existing information from social networking sites. Guru.com is approved by Facebook, google+, and LinkedIn for Social Login through making our Privacy Policy publicly available and easily accessible. Our Privacy Policy also gives our users the scope of the data collected and use of that data collected on Guru.com. 

By logging in through Facebook, Google+, LinkedIn, or any other Social Login we may accept in the future, you consent to our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service as well as the Privacy Policy and Terms of Service of Facebook, Google+, LinkedIn, and etc. Please review the Terms of Service and Privacy Policy for the Social Login you may be using to determine the collection and usage of data per the previously mentioned Social Login services you may be using. 

### Disclosure of All Financial Transactions on User Profiles Disclaimer

Guru.com discloses all of the financial transactions on profiles of both the Employers and Freelancers for the benefit of all users. The disclosure of the financial transactions is for the benefit of all users in making intelligent and informed choices in regards to accepting jobs from Employers and hiring Freelancers.
